

# Maite Lizarraga Téllez

Junior Data Scientist / Data Analyst

Madrid, hybrid or remote

Absolutely passionate about data, IT and math, and after having spent the last 5 years working in Paris, France, I am looking for a new permanent role as a Junior Data Scientist / Data Analyst in Madrid, Spain.

Contact: +34 623 10 10 73 / maite.lizarraga@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maite-lizarraga-tellez Github: maitelizarraga.github.io

### Education —

March 2024 - Ongoing: Data Analytics Bootcamp - Immune Technology Institute - Madrid and remote

2023 - Ongoing: Grado en Applied Data Science (first-second year student) - UOC (Universitat Oberta de Catalunya) - Remote 2010: A.S. International Business - Tompkins Cortland Community College - State University of New York - USA and remote

2003 - 2006: Multilingual Management Assistant - ISSA (Universidad de Navarra) - San Sebastián, Spain

## Courses and Certifications —

August 2024: IT Specialist - Databases Certification - Pearson Education Certiport, Remote. see badge

July 2024: IT Specialist - Data Analytics Certification - Pearson Education Certiport, Remote. see badge

May 2024: IT Specialist - Python Certification - Pearson Education Certiport, Remote. see badge

2106 - 2017: Web Development and Javascript short courses - AEPI - Asociación Española de Programadores Informáticos, Madrid.

#### Data Skills —

**Bootcamp:** Python, Mysql, Data Analysis & Visualization (Pandas, PowerBI, Tableau, Seaborn, Plotnine), Machine/Deep Learning basics. **University:** Python, R, PostgreSQL, Data Analysis and Visualization (Matplotlib, Scipy, Numpy, Pandas). Algebra & Statistics. ML basics. **Tools:** Spyder, Google Colab, Jupyter Notebooks, RStudio, PgAdmin4, Excel, Mysql Workbench, Visual Studio Code, Git & Github.

Languages — First languages: Spanish and Basque / Bilingual: French and English / Lower intermediate: German

**Strengths** — I am a very analytical, math-loving, detail-oriented and rigorous professional.

# Work Experience -

## Supply Chain Administrator - Hana Group

Food Retail (Sushi stands) | Jul 2023 - Apr 2024 / Levallois-Perret (92), Paris, France

- A-Z management of fresh salmon supply for France and Belgium (~600 stands) and operations support. Pivot tables and EDI.
- Participated in the new salmon 2024 contract negotiations, created new supply chain processes and dashboards in Excel.

## Sustainable Clothing Marketplace Creator - The Slow Market

Sustainable Clothing E-commerce | Jan 2022 / Aug 2022 Paris-Hendaye, France

• Prestashop marketplace coding, supplier sourcing, market research.

#### E-Commerce Supply Chain Administrator - 1001Hobbies

Retail E-Commerce | Apr 2019 - Jan 2022 / Paris (11ème), France

- Improvement of supply-chain strategy and implementation of IT tools (ERP, Mysql, Excel dashboards).
- Logistics management in the Lyon warehouse: just-in-time stock management and supplier delivery control.
- Supplier ordering (40 suppliers, approx. 150,000 active references) and invoice control, incoming & outgoing payments, refunds.

## Supply Chain and Logistics Administrator - ByDehesa

Food B2B and E-Commerce | Sept 2018 - Jan 2019 / Rungis (94), Paris, France

- Stock management, inventories, delivery times, disputes, non-payments, etc. France and export: Switzerland and Hong Kong.
- Logistics: management of various service providers (Stef, Delanchy, Chronopost) for dry, fresh and frozen products.

#### Junior Frontend Developer - Oldboy Creative Development & Kunn Sistemas

Web Development | Mar 2017 - Feb 2018 / Madrid, Spain

• Web development: HTML, CSS, Less, Sass, Javascript Vanilla, JQuery, Liferay, Trello, Jira, Slack.

## Country Manager Assistant - Bio c' Bon Espagne

Retail - Sustainable Supermarkets | Oct 2014 - Sept 2016 / Madrid, Spain

- Bio c' Bon's Spanish subsidiary set up. Store openings. Contributions to the country development strategy.
- Financial/Accounting: Weekly sales analysis, cash flow control. Supplier settlements and litigation. Payroll.
- Procurement: Negotiation of commercial leases for new stores and purchasing conditions with suppliers. Inventory control.
- General problem-solving: deadlines, prices, discounts, quality of work, materials, compliance with safety regulations.
- IT: Together with the teams in Paris, set-up of store IT systems: POS terminals, internet network, server, digital price tags, etc.

#### Clinical Trial Assistant (CTA) - Ondax Scientific (currently Argenta Group)

Pharmaceutical Industry | Nov 2010 - Aug 2013 / Guipuzcoa, Spain

• Setup of clinical trial files and data collection software (Clinsight). Management of partner veterinary clinics and translations.

# Case Team Assistant - The Boston Consulting Group (BCG)

Management Consultancy | Oct 2006 - Dec 2009 / Madrid

Document, dashboard and graphic creation on Excel and PowerPoint